<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>https://www.openquestion.net</id>
  <title>Open Question</title>
  <updated>2022-02-01T21:52:01.047840+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
    <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://www.openquestion.net" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/feed.atom" rel="self"/>
  <contributor>
    <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
    <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
  </contributor>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <icon>https://www.openquestion.net/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://www.openquestion.net/apple-touch-icon.png</logo>
  <rights>Copyright © Daniel Sissom</rights>
  <subtitle>a blog of existential crises</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/tech/001.html</id>
    <title>Tech-001 - Roll your own static blog engine (Part 1)</title>
    <updated>2022-01-12T22:51:28.439453-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Roll your own static blog engine (Part 1)</h1>
<h2>Project layout and hosting with git</h2>
<hr />
<p>As the first tech post here, I figured a natural choice would be a walk through
on how I make and host the site itself.  There's a bit much to try to cram into
one post, so this will be the start of a short series on my development and
publishing process.</p>
<p>I create and host this blog completely for free using a number of open source
tools for site generation and GitHub pages for static hosting.  Creating a site
this way works really well for any static site---that is, one that doesn't rely
on server-side scripting or databases (though, I do plan on writing about how to
add in those capabilities in a future post)---and should scale well to even
large traffic volumes.</p>
<hr />
<h3>Project layout and git setup</h3>
<p>For a web project that's going to be published to a static site host, we'll need
a directory for the source files and a directory for the generated html, css,
and other content that is uploaded to the server.  I don't suppose there are any
canonical locations for these, but I've found putting the source directory
inside the output directory works pretty well.  I'm sure the inverse would be
just fine too.  Including directories for css and javascript, a boilerplate
project layout for one of my sites might look something like this:</p>
<pre><code>./sitename.com/
	- index.html
	- script/
	- src/
		- index.pug
		- script/
		- style/
	- style/
</code></pre>
<p>The simplest way I've found for handling version control here is just to create
two separate git repositories.  The first one in <code>sitename.com/</code> will be for
pushing content to the server.  The second in <code>src/</code> will be for actually
versioning the work you do on the site.  It is arguable that you should just use
one repository since the content of <code>sitename.com/</code> is directly related to
<code>src/</code>, but after hacking around on that for too long, I found it way simpler
just to use two repos.</p>
<p>So, to get started:</p>
<pre><code>$ cd /directory/where/you/put/web/projects/
$ mkdir sitename.com
$ cd sitename.com
$ git init
</code></pre>
<p>This creates your site directory and initializes a git repo inside.  Next, we'll
create the <code>src/</code> directory and ignore it:</p>
<pre><code>$ mkdir src
$ echo &quot;src&quot; &gt; .gitignore
$ git add .
$ git commit
</code></pre>
<p>This keeps your pre-compiled source from ending up hosted to the public and
allows us to create a second git repo in the <code>src/</code> directory:</p>
<pre><code>$ cd src
$ git init
$ touch .gitignore
$ git add .
$ git commit
</code></pre>
<p>We now have two independent git repositories to hold both the source code/markup
and the resulting generated content for the site.  If you don't otherwise use
git, you may need to set up some configuration variables like your name and
email address:</p>
<pre><code>$ git config --global user.name &quot;Your Name&quot;
$ git config --global user.email &quot;email@host.com&quot;
</code></pre>
<p>I also set the <code>user.signingkey</code> and <code>commit.gpgsign</code> options so I can use my
Yubikey to sign commits with GPG, but that set up may have to be it's own post
someday . . .</p>
<hr />
<h3>Hosting</h3>
<p>Now that we have a git repository set up, we need a place to push it to.  I use
GitHub Pages for hosting this site, as it's free for static sites and easy to
publish to with a simple <code>git push</code> command.  There are plenty of other options,
from dedicated services to running your own servers, but I find GitHub offers a
nice balance of practicality with free-ness and keeps me from having to worry
about uptime.</p>
<p>Create a new repository from your GitHub account and give it the name of your
site.  Then set the GitHub repo as upstream to the build repository created
earlier:</p>
<pre><code>$ git remote add origin git@github.com:&lt;username&gt;/&lt;reponame&gt;.git
$ git push -u origin master
</code></pre>
<p>Make sure to do this from the <code>sitename.com</code> repository, not the <code>src</code>
repository, as we want to keep that private.  Now we can commit a couple of
files and push up to our new host.  Here, the CNAME file will help with pointing
a domain name at the site in the next step.</p>
<pre><code>$ echo Hello. &gt; index.html
$ echo www.sitename.com &gt; CNAME
$ git add .
$ git commit
$ git push
</code></pre>
<p>On the GitHub repo's settings page, go to the Pages tab to configure how your
site will be served.  Choose the branch you want to serve from (probably master)
and set the custom domain field to your domain if it's not set already.</p>
<p>Enable the Enforce HTTPS option if you're serving directly from GitHub, or you
can leave it blank if proxying through something like Cloudflare.  This is a
newer option for GitHub Pages.  When I first set up the site, this wasn't
available, and the only way to get HTTPS on a custom domain was to proxy traffic
through a CDN like Cloudflare to allow/force secure connections.</p>
<p>At the registrar for your domain name (or wherever the DNS server for your site
is), add two CNAME records to point to the GitHub repo.  First, add a CNAME
record to redirect <code>sitename.com</code> to <code>www.sitename.com</code>.  Then add a second
CNAME to point <code>www</code> to <code>&lt;yourusername&gt;.github.io</code>.  GitHub can then use the
CNAME file we committed earlier to direct requests to the appropriate page.  Now
(at least once the DNS settings have had time to propagate), you should be able
to type your domain name in a browser and see the Hello text from the index.html
page in the repository.</p>
<p>From this point, it's all about creating your site however you want.  Whenever
you want to publish your updates, all you have to do is</p>
<pre><code>$ git add .
$ git commit
$ git push
</code></pre>
<p>In future parts of this series, we'll get more into the site creation itself,
including HTML templating with PugJS, build automation with Make, and RSS feed
generation with Python.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/s2j74x/tech001_roll_your_own_static_blog_engine_part_1/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/tech/001.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<hr />
]]></summary>
    <published>2022-01-12T22:51:28.439453-06:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/tech/000.html</id>
    <title>Tech-000 - Tech Introduction</title>
    <updated>2022-01-12T19:51:09.110945-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Tech Introduction</h1>
<p>Before I start posting articles for the tech-focused side of the blog, I thought
I'd make a quick post about what my plans are here.</p>
<p>My background is in computational astrophysics, moving toward software
development and devops, so I've had exposure to a wide selection of
computational methods.  I've done high performance scientific computing for
astronomy simulations, data reduction and analysis, machine learning, Linux
system administration and automation, security management, web development, and
microservice deployment.</p>
<p>At least to start with, tech posts here will focus mostly on the software side
of things and cover topics like Linux tricks, analysis methods, backup schemes,
data security, or whatever else I've learned from developing and deploying
software that might be useful to somebody.  This probably won't end up being an
academic dive into esoteric computational methods, but instead a more practical
set of tutorials for making the most of your digital resources.</p>
<p>So, check back soon, and let me know in the comments if there are any topics
that you'd like to see.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/q6x76p/tech000_tech_introduction/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/tech/000.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p>Before I start posting articles for the tech-focused side of the blog, I thought
I'd make a quick post about what my plans are here.</p>
]]></summary>
    <published>2021-10-12T12:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/003.html</id>
    <title>Theorics-003 - Hedge your bets</title>
    <updated>2021-10-12T22:19:40.787951-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Hedge your bets</h1>
<h2>( . . . if it makes sense)</h2>
<p>I can be an . . . <em>opinionated</em> person.  My wife often likes to remind me that,
before we were married, more than one of my family members warned her that I can
be overly stubborn when I think I'm right.  And who doesn't think they're right
most of the time?  I have the luxury of often being able to spend the time to do
some basic research to come up with the &quot;best&quot; answer when forming an opinion.
(Vim is the best editor.  Fight me.)  But what if I'm wrong?</p>
<p>Every one of us is continually bathed in a sea of opinions.  As I discussed in a
previous post, we choose so much of what we do based on seeking reinforcement of
our beliefs.  It is so easy to end up only being exposed to views you already
agree with, and thus it can often seem unfathomable that we're wrong.  Maybe,
&quot;literally every person I know does that.&quot;  Or, &quot;every comment I've read on this
site agrees that it's not true.&quot;  This can be such a difficult cognitive bias to
overcome.  So much so that it becomes imperative to question even our most
strongly held beliefs --- <em>especially</em> our most strongly held beliefs.</p>
<p>I am by no means saying that all views should be given equal weight or validity.
However, admitting the possibility, however small, that the opposing viewpoint
is, in actuality, the very real truth of reality leads to an inevitable thought
experiment:  what would that mean?  If I'm wrong, what consequences does that
imply?  What changes?  What else would I need to rethink?  What do I do
differently?</p>
<p>I find it most helpful to consider a hypothetical case in which what I believe
to be true has no consequences if true, regardless of whether or not I believe
it's true.  Conversely, the opposing view would have severe negative
consequences if it were true and I thought the opposite.</p>
<p>As a fabricated example, suppose there is a gun sitting on a table that I <em>know</em>
is unloaded.  I removed the magazine, emptied the chamber, did a visual
inspection.  I verified that the gun is unloaded, myself, in every way possible,
and it has not left my sight since doing so.  Then someone walks up, picks up
the gun, points it at me, and says they will pull the trigger in 5 seconds.</p>
<p>I now have a choice.  I can stand there, confident in my knowledge and wait for
a hollow click, or I can simply move out of the way.  Of course, I'm going to
move out of the way.  But why?  I am sure I am right.  All of my observations
say I have nothing to worry about.  But being wrong has very real, very
life-and-death consequences.  I gain nothing by standing still, even if I'm in
no actual danger.  It's trivial to perform the necessary actions to avoid the
consequences of being wrong.  So, despite full confidence in my belief, I will
take action contrary to my belief.  That's the better choice, because of the
severity of the consequences of being wrong.</p>
<p>(Obviously, this is a contrived example.  Life is rarely so black and white.
Everything is a continuum, and nothing is this cut and dry.  But this is a
thought experiment to serve as a baseline.)</p>
<p>While the previous example demonstrates the consideration of extreme
consequences, it relies on two conditions that cannot always be assumed:
reasonable ease of action and a non-trivial possibility that I was wrong.  As a
further example, now suppose that someone comes up to me and tells me that
tomorrow Earth's gravity will reverse, and we'll all be flung into space.  Of
course, I don't believe them, but once again, that's a pretty severe
consequence.</p>
<p>This time, I would say it's pretty safe to ignore the crackpot.  But what
changed this time?  The consequence is even more severe that before.  Not only
am I risking my own life, but the lives of every human on the planet!  That's a
pretty big ask.  Again, <strong>probability</strong> and <strong>actionability</strong>.</p>
<p>Before with the gun, while I was confident, there was also the possibility that
I had missed something.  Maybe I didn't do as good a job as I thought clearing
it as safe.  Maybe the stranger performed some slight of hand and swapped it out
before I could notice.  There's always some chance.  This time, though, the
gravity reversing claims of our stranger would require our entire understanding
of the physical Universe to be completely and utterly wrong.  It would require
tomorrow to somehow behave so vastly different than the billions of years
previous that no other observation ever made would make any sense whatsoever.
The probability of this person being right is vanishingly small.</p>
<p>Furthermore, even if this crazy notion is somehow actually correct and going to
happen, what could I do about it?  Maybe I could go home and start nailing down
my furniture so it doesn't float away?  Maybe tether myself to something solid?
Those feel like things I could reasonably do.  But hold on . . . the floor I've
nailed my furniture to is sitting on a concrete foundation that's just poured
into the dirt underneath.  That's a pretty minor tensile force compared to the
newfound gravitational repulsion.  I should probably anchor my house to some
bedrock.  Great, now I have to get some construction crews out here on less than
a day's notice.  But wait again . . . that bedrock isn't molecularly bonded to
the rest of the Earth; it's pretty much just sitting there due to gravity too.
Oh, and the air.  There won't be any of that around anymore either.  This is
getting out of hand. . .</p>
<p>This is obviously reduction to absurdism, but it underlies the balance that must
happen when evaluating positions you don't agree with.  Response to other
possibilities has to be informed and influenced by the severity of the
consequences to being wrong, the probability of that outcome, and the
actionability of the solution.</p>
<p>At least for the moment, I've tried to actively avoid directly talking about
current events, political ideologies, or hot-button issues.  We're building a
tool box for critical thinking, regardless of stance on a particular issue, and
I don't want someone to ignore something that might be helpful only because I
come down on some topic differently than they do.  However, distribution and
ingestion of misinformation seems to be at an all time high.  Please don't think
I'm talking only about &quot;them,&quot; whoever &quot;them&quot; is to you.  I'm talking to you,
you reading this article, regardless of your political background, your
religious predilections, or your scientific literacy.  And I'm talking to me,
because I have to remind myself every day that I don't---can't---know
everything.</p>
<p>Could you be wrong?  Is there even the slightest possibility that the millions
or billions of humans on this planet that see things differently than you might
have a point?  Everyone has an opinion, but that doesn't mean you have to stake
your life on it.  Be kind to those that think differently than you.  Be open to
being wrong sometimes.  Think about what it would mean if you are.  And, if it's
reasonable to do so, hedge your bets.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/q6vwm1/theorics003_hedge_your_bets/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/003.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p>I can be an . . . <em>opinionated</em> person.  My wife often likes to remind me that,
before we were married, more than one of my family members warned her that I can
be overly stubborn when I think I'm right.  And who doesn't think they're right
most of the time?  I have the luxury of often being able to spend the time to do
some basic research to come up with the &quot;best&quot; answer when forming an opinion.
(Vim is the best editor.  Fight me.)  But what if I'm wrong?</p>
]]></summary>
    <published>2021-08-25T12:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/002.html</id>
    <title>Theorics-002 - Play the odds</title>
    <updated>2021-10-12T22:19:40.787951-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Play the odds</h1>
<p>In statistical mechanics, a foundational concept is that the most likely
macrostate is the one with the overwhelming majority of consistent microstates.
That is a lot to unpack in one sentence if you haven't had a stat mech course,
but the concept ends up being pretty intuitive (bear with some hand-wavy physics
for just a moment).  A macrostate can be thought of as a measurable quantity of
a system, like the air temperature in a room, while a microstate is a specific
configuration of components of a system, like the specific positions and
velocities of all the molecules of the air in a room.</p>
<p>The particles making up the air could be in a tremendously large number of
different configurations.  Random positions and velocities of each particle
could result in microstate where every single particle was cramped over in a
corner, leaving the rest of the room in a vacuum.  Or they could all end up with
velocities pointing the same direction, creating a strong breeze out of nowhere.
However, we would never expect those outcomes, because compared to the
vanishingly small number of configurations consistent with that &quot;weird&quot;
macrostate, there are many, many orders of magnitude more configurations
consistent with a &quot;normal&quot; macrostate where the particles are distributed evenly
throughout the room with velocities consistent with measured physical laws.</p>
<p>Imagine you were sitting in our air-filled room.  If I were to ask you about the
exact position and speed of a specific particle, you wouldn't be able to tell
me.  In fact, even beyond the practical limitations of answering such a
question, there exists a more fundamental limit on how well that question can be
answered due to quantum mechanics (we'll save that for another post . . .).
However, if I asked what the temperature of the room was, it would be stupidly
easy to give me an answer, despite the unknowability of the movement of the
individual particles that make up what a temperature is really a measure of.  A
thermometer would give a fairly precise answer, but even just using the feeling
of your skin, you could hazard a pretty good guess.</p>
<p>Your temperature measurement, in addition to masking the complexity of the
physical world with a statistical measurement, also makes an assumption about
about the whole room using a measurement from just one location.  Here, I'm not
talking about convection currents and temperature gradients from elevation
(which are totally a thing that can make your measurement less valid), but
instead the assumption that you are making a measurement at a non-special time
and place.</p>
<p>It could be entirely possible, going back to the previous microstate concept,
that your temperature measurement just happened to occur right before all the
particles in the room ended up in the corner by pure chance, or that a little
sphere around your thermometer had a normal distribution of velocities to give
you your reading, but all the rest of the air was suddenly much colder because
all the molecules bumped into each other in just the right way to slow them
down.  While these circumstances are &quot;possible,&quot; no one would expect them to be
the case, because the chance of that one special state occurring would be
completely dwarfed by the vast number of particle configurations that lead to
your measurement being representative of the evenly distributed properties.</p>
<p>All of this has been a long-winded and probably overly complex illustration to
make a simple analogy (you'll probably have to get used to that kind of thing
here).  You can't know everything.  I would, as briefly introduced in the
previous post, even extend this as far as saying you can't really know anything.
But, this fundamental limitation on absolute knowledge doesn't mean that you
can't have a pretty good guess.</p>
<p>We can't know every underlying complexity of the world around us.  We can't
prove that something happened.  We can't really prove anything.  But we can
gather evidence.  We can see trends.  We can extrapolate.  We can predict.</p>
<p>There is no mathematical proof that my senses give me accurate information, that
I'm not just a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain">Boltzmann brain</a> randomly assembled by chance from
interstellar dust with my current memories pre-formed.  I can, however, assign
estimated probabilities to possible realities and behave accordingly.  If I,
say, decide (as an arbitrary example) that there's a 99.999% probability that
reality is as it seems (and we are all biological life forms inhabiting the
surface of a rocky terrestrial planet), and there's a 0.001% chance that I am a
Boltzmann brain, existing only for the briefest instant as the only
consciousness in the Universe, it's probably pretty safe to behave as though the
former is the truth, despite the inability to unquestionably prove the validity
of that option.</p>
<p>I have come to a point where I can no longer accept anything as absolutely
certain.  This is not to say that truth does not exist.  Systems exist in a
certain state regardless of our knowledge of them or even our ability to have
knowledge of them.  However, any claim to know something as a certainty seems
utter nonsense.  There are too many abstraction layers between our conception
and the reality of the physical world, each with an underlying set of
assumptions that allow us to process and make decisions.</p>
<p>So what then?  Are we doomed to ignorance and instinct?  If nothing can be known
about the world, how do we do anything?  How do we build skyscrapers or put
people in space or tie our shoes?</p>
<p>In a word:  models.  Predictive models underlie our every conception about the
physical world, whether or not we are explicitly aware of them.  We will discuss
models more in depth in a future post, but the concept of models informing our
decisions is fairly straightforward.</p>
<p>What <em>is</em> gravity?  That's a pretty complex question.  Good luck finding someone
to answer it.  But you don't have to understand general relativity to catch a
ball.  You make observations of flying balls over the course of your life,
incorporate that input into your mental model of how balls fall through the air,
and use that model to make a prediction of where the ball will land.  Are you
making calculations for orbits of GPS satellites or black hole dynamics?  Then
yes, you will need some GR for that.  But again, even general relativity is just
a predictive model that, while matching predictions to observed outcomes
extremely precisely, only gives us an abstraction of the underlying reality, not
the underlying reality itself.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, general relativity and a toddler's prediction of how a ball will
bounce are the same kind of thing.  However, the difference comes in when we
consider the predictive power of the models, and thus the relative probability
that each model is a good description of reality.  Evidence of predictive power
is really the only thing we have, and can have, to go on.</p>
<p>So, can you <em>know</em> something?  I would say, fundamentally, no.  But, the
predictive power of experimentally verified models lets us have a pretty good
idea.  Between options, even in the face of fundamental ignorance, we can make
the choice with the higher <em>probability</em> of being right.  Most of the time, the
odds are overwhelming.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/q6vvrw/theorics002_play_the_odds/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/002.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p>In statistical mechanics, a foundational concept is that the most likely
macrostate is the one with the overwhelming majority of consistent microstates.
That is a lot to unpack in one sentence if you haven't had a stat mech course,
but the concept ends up being pretty intuitive (bear with some hand-wavy physics
for just a moment).  A macrostate can be thought of as a measurable quantity of
a system, like the air temperature in a room, while a microstate is a specific
configuration of components of a system, like the specific positions and
velocities of all the molecules of the air in a room.</p>
]]></summary>
    <published>2021-08-04T12:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/001.html</id>
    <title>Theorics-001 - Who knows?</title>
    <updated>2021-10-12T22:19:40.787951-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Who knows?</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;The only thing I know for certain is that I know nothing.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How much do you know?  Consider for a moment the vast amount of information that
you've accumulated in your lifetime:  the facts and trivia you learned through
school and work, your day to day experiences, the memory of your internal
thoughts and feelings over the years, what you've read, what you've seen with
your own two eyes...</p>
<p>It's easy to take for granted that we know something.  The human brain is
unparalleled in its ability to make short-term predictions extrapolated from
sensory input.  At its heart, this ability has to rely on the assumption that
said sensory input is valid.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the same mental processes that let us catch a ball thrown through
the air or have successful social interactions also cause us to favor our
existing mental model of the world over new information that makes us question
previous assumptions.  This can manifest in a number of ways, from logical
fallacies in otherwise well-intentioned discussions to social media echo
chambers that only reinforce already-held beliefs.</p>
<p>We build our entire worldview on our previous assumptions.  Obviously it would
be an impossible task to rethink everything we've ever known from first
principles every time we had to make a decision.  It's a much more efficient and
practical necessity to assume what we already know is pretty much true and tweak
it as new incoming information comes in.  This works great most of the time.
Questioning the fundamental nature of reality doesn't help you buy bananas at
the supermarket.</p>
<p>However, these adaptations that make it possible to cope with the day to day
world make it nearly impossible to accept information that would fundamentally
conflict with our preconceived worldview.  We will hold on to any shred of
anecdote to support what we already believe in the face of a mountain of
evidence to the contrary.  We will shut out those we once counted friends if
they share something sufficiently misaligned our beliefs.  We will choose where
we get our news and entertainment, where we shop, who we spend time with, even
where we live, based on creating an environment that doesn't challenge our
views.</p>
<p>Once we &quot;know&quot; something, it's exceedingly difficult to take a step back and
really think about <em>how</em> or <em>why</em> we know.  Taking this to its logical
conclusion results in the deepest rabbit hole of all rabbit holes, but I think
it's worth the effort.  It's turtles all the way down, but we'll dig as far as
we can.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/q6vus6/theorics001_who_knows/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/001.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p>How much do you know?  Consider for a moment the vast amount of information that
you've accumulated in your lifetime:  the facts and trivia you learned through
school and work, your day to day experiences, the memory of your internal
thoughts and feelings over the years, what you've read, what you've seen with
your own two eyes...</p>
]]></summary>
    <published>2021-08-01T12:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/000.html</id>
    <title>Theorics-000 - Introduction</title>
    <updated>2021-10-12T22:19:40.787951-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sissom</name>
      <email>daniel@openquestion.net</email>
    </author>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<h1>Introduction</h1>
<h2>(or, What Are We Doing Here?)</h2>
<p>Reboot.  I made this site a few years ago and never ended up writing anything
for it past an introductory post.  I've decided to start it up again and see if
I actually end up posting this time, so here goes...</p>
<p>As an aside, I'll probably re-write this page with a proper intro post after
getting a couple of blog entries up.  Welcome back, and stay tuned.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/comments/q6vtzf/theorics000_introduction/">Comments for this post</a> are on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/openquestion/">/r/openquestion</a>
subreddit.</p>
]]></content>
    <link href="https://www.openquestion.net/theorics/000.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p>Reboot.  I made this site a few years ago and never ended up writing anything
for it past an introductory post.  I've decided to start it up again and see if
I actually end up posting this time, so here goes...</p>
]]></summary>
    <published>2021-08-01T12:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
